Susannah McInerney

susannah.mci@gmail.com / 828.273.2032 / Providence, RI susannahmcinerney.com

Experienced professional with a focused ability to think strategically within the needs of a creative environment through excellent problem solving and interpersonal skills. Strong knowledge of project management specifically for floral design and event planning. Highly organized self-starter with an eye for process improvement and ability to multitask while maintaining attention to detail.

Education

Savannah College of Art and Design | Savannah, GA

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Fashion Design

- · GPA 3.7, Dean's List, graduated cum laude
- Awarded Portfolio Scholarship by SCAD for apparel, painting, and jewelry design

Industry Experience

Petit Jardin en Ville | Philadelphia, PA | Jan 2018-May 2019 Floral Design Assistant/Studio Manager

- Able to demonstrate floral design skills in a variety of styles, capturing the creative direction unique to each venue, client, or bride
- Provided outstanding customer service through resolving customer's questions and needs and continuously nurturing existing and new client relationships
- Managed studio logistics including daily order intake and processing, set-up and break down of store, overseeing of visual merchandising
- Contributed in the design process from proposal stage to execution, designing floral and plant pieces for weddings, photo shoots, pop-up events, retail spaces, and more
- Ensured timely and efficient processing of florals in a high volume studio with several product deliveries per day. We focused on high end, seasonal, and delicate blooms to be handled with precision and care
- Trusted with organization and execution of event pieces, weekly client orders, and daily customer orders.
 Orchestrated delivery, set-up and breakdown for weddings and other high demand events while working as a liaison with other vendors

Anthrothpologie | Philadelphia, PA | August 2015-October 2016 Design Coordinator

- Managed team communications on a logistical level, presenting season calendars and new best practices to confirm deadlines are met
- Worked closely with cross-functional and overseas teams to keep a calculated perspective in daily tasks, project execution, and online systems accuracy
- Assisted with meeting prep to ensure material is presented in an exciting and fresh way with emphasis on the brand identity
- Creative problem solving and troubleshooting to outline the responsibilities of this new role as it relates to the greater team

Stella & Dot Design Studio | New York, NY | Jan 2015-May 2015 Design Coordinator

- Point person for team communications and season calendar, particularly as it relates to tech pack development and season hand off
- Maintained the flexibility to focus on various design related projects as they arise to ensure big picture brand priorities are met, coordinating strategies between domestic and international offices
- Ability to work independently within a fast paced setting of quick decisions, immediate deadlines, and changing needs

Jones New York | New York, NY | May 2012-October 2014 Design Support Coordinator

- Understanding of all division's work stages and needs through online systems to ensure Design is coordinating efforts within the larger team to remain consistent with the brand calendar
- Unique position in the Woven/Knits Design teams acting as liaison between various departments including Tech, R&D, Product Development, Planning, Sales, and Merchandising
- Worked across several brands to ensure a calculated perspective is kept in daily tasks- including season color development, season hand off, and communicating style changes

Hansae Co. Ltd. | New York, NY | February 2011–Jan 2012 Assistant Designer | Accounts: Target, Gap, Aéropostale, VS Pink

- Developed all aspects of design process from initial direction and fabric selection, to tech packs and customer meetings for all categories including women's, intimates, juniors, and active
- Played intricate role in creating quarterly trend book through extensive research, creative concept meetings, and execution of team ideas culminating in traveling internationally for trend presentations
- Account driven market research, including making monthly trend-forward design reports referenced by both domestic and overseas teams

Contributions

Dîner en Blanc | 2018

 Official florist for the Philadelphia chapter of the worldwide cultural dining event

PAWS Volunteering Group | 2016-2018

 Working to enrich local community through monthly events that support animal shelters and adoption